Finding Aid for Herbert F. Baker Papers 1904-1930
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Herbert F. Baker Papers 1904-1930
Baker, Herbert F., 1862-1930.
855 AC Aa 2
Republican state representative, 1907-1912, speaker of the Michigan House of Representatives, 1911, state senator, 1919-1922, and official of the Farmers' National Council, the National Gleaner Federation, the Michigan State Grange and other farm and insurance organizations; includes correspondence, clippings, photographs and scrapbooks, concerning his political and business activities.
5 linear feet
1 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated in 1977 by Tom Baker (donor no. 6066 ), son of Herbert F. Baker.
The collection is open for research.
Herbert F. Baker was Republican state representative, 1907-1912; speaker of the Michigan House of Representatives, 1911; state senator, 1919-1922; and official of the Farmers' National Council, the National Gleaner Federation, the Michigan State Grange and other farm and insurance organizations
The Herber F. Baker papers are organized into three series; correspondence and Miscellaneous Papers and Scrapbooks, and Photographs
The collection spans the dates 1904-1926 and contains five linear feet of correspondence, clippings, photographs and scrapbooks concerning Baker's political and business activities.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Michigan.; Baker, Herbert F., 1862-1930.; Universities and colleges--Michigan.; Dutch Americans--Michigan.; Education--Michigan.; Elections--Michigan--1920.; Elections--Michigan--1924.; Elections--Michigan--1926.; German Americans--Michigan.; Insurance--Michigan.; Michigan State Grange.; Polish Americans--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Michigan--Politics and government--1917-1921.; Michigan--Politics and government--1922-1928.; Progressive Party (1912); Progressivism (United States politics); Republican Party (Mich.); Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Women--Suffrage--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Baker, Herbert F., 1862-1930.; Barns.; Cheboygan County (Mich.); Cheboygan County (Mich.). Board of Supervisors.; Construction.; Hats--ca. 1910.; Legislators--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Women.
Contributors:
All American Co-operative Commission.; Ancient Order of Gleaners.; Anti-Saloon League of Michigan.; Bourne, Jonathan, 1855-1940.; Briggs, Walter Owen, 1877-1952.; Campbell, Colin Percy, 1877-; Clardy, Kit Francis, 1892-; Conference for Progressive Political Action.; Conference of Progressive State Granges.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Cramton, Louis C. (Louis Convers), b. 1875.; Currie, Gilbert, 1882-1960.; DeFoe, Murl Holcomb, 1879-; Detroit Municipal League.; Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.; Earle, Horatio Sawyer, 1855-1935.; Ellis, George Edwin, 1864-; Employers' Association of Detroit.; Farmer's Federal Tax League of America.; Farmers' National Committee on Postal Reform.; Farmers' National Committee on Transportation.; Farmers' National Committee on War Finance.; Farmers' National Council.; Fellows, Grant, 1865-1929.; Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.; Fletcher, Frank Ward, 1853-1922.; Fuller, Oramel B., b. 1858.; Gardner, Obadiah, 1850-1938.; Salling, Hanson, and Company (Grayling, Mich.); Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Grenell, Judson.; Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Hampton, George P., d. 1921.; Helme, James W., 1860-1938.; Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967.; Howe, Frederic Clemson, 1867-1940.; James, William Francis, 1873-1945.; Jeffries, Edward, 1900-1950; Ketcham, John Clark, 1873-1941.; King, Paul Howard, 1879-1942.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925.; Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.; League of American Sportsmen.; Lemke, William, 1878-1950.; Loud, George Alvin, 1852-1925.; Lowden, Frank O. (Frank Orren), 1861-1943.; Lutheran Church-Missouri Synod. Michigan District. Lutheran Schools Committee.; McGregor, Tracy William, 1869-1936.; Mapes, Carl Edgar, 1874-1939.; Marsh, Benjamin Clarke, 1877-1952.; Martel, Frank Xavier, 1888-; Martindale, Frederick C.; Michigan business farmer.; Michigan Home Rule League.; Michigan Potato Growers Exchange.; Michigan State Federation of Women's Clubs.; Modern Woodmen of America.; Musselman, Amos S., b. 1851.; National Milk Producers Federation.; National Nonpartisan League.; National Progressive Republican League.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Michigan Federation of Labor.; Michigan. Legislature.; People's Legislative Service.; People's Reconstruction League.; Pettigrew, Richard Franklin, 1848-1926.; Powers, Perry Francis, 1857-1945.; Progressive Republicans' League of Michigan.; Progressive Voters League of Michigan.; Rural Credit League of America.; Scott, Frank Douglas, 1878-1951.; Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934.; Smith, John W., 1883-; Smith, William Alden, 1859-1932.; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Wallace, Henry Cantwell, 1866-1924.; Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.; Watkins, Lucius Whitney, 1873-; Wesselius, Sybrant, b. 1859.; Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953.
Form and Genre:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Tintypes.
- Correspondence
  - 1904-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1906 (Box 1)
  - 1907 (Box 1)
  - 1908 (Box 1)
  - 1909 (Box 1)
  - 1910 (Box 1)
  - 1911 undated (Box 1)
  - January 1-10, 1911 (Box 1)
  - January 11-20, 1911 (Box 1)
  - January 21-31, 1911 (Box 1)
  - February 1-10, 1911 (Box 1)
  - February 11-20, 1911 (Box 1)
  - February 21-28, 1911 (Box 1)
  - March 1-15, 1911 (Box 1)
  - March 16-31, 1911 (Box 1)
  - April-June 1911 (Box 1)
  - July 1911 (Box 1)
  - August 1911 (Box 1)
  - September 1911 (Box 1)
  - October 1911 (Box 1)
  - November 1911 (Box 1)
  - December 1-10, 1911 (Box 1)
  - December 11-20, 1911 (Box 1)
  - December 21-31, 1911 (Box 1)
  - 1912 undated (Box 1)
  - January 1-15, 1912 (Box 1)
  - January 16-31, 1912 (Box 1)
  - February 1-14, 1912 (Box 1)
  - February 15-29, 1912 (Box 1)
  - March 1-15, 1912 (Box 1)
  - March 16-31, 1912 (Box 1)
  - April 1912 (Box 1)
  - May 1912 (Box 1)
  - June 1912 (Box 1)
  - July 1912 (Box 1)
  - August-December 1912 (Box 1)
  - 1913-1914 (Box 1)
  - January-February 1915 (Box 1)
  - March-June 1915 (Box 1)
  - July-September 1915 (Box 1)
  - October-December 1915 (Box 1)
  - January-February 1916 (Box 2)
  - March-April 1916 (Box 2)
  - May 1916 (Box 2)
  - June 1916 (Box 2)
  - July-August 1916 (Box 2)
  - September 1916 (Box 2)
  - October 1916 (Box 2)
  - November-December 1916 (Box 2)
  - January 1917 (Box 2)
  - February-March 1917 (Box 2)
  - April 1917 (Box 2)
  - May-June 1917 (Box 2)
  - July-September 1917 (Box 2)
  - October-December 1917 (Box 2)
  - January 1918 (Box 2)
  - February-March 1918 (Box 2)
  - April 1918 (Box 2)
  - May-June 1918 (Box 2)
  - July 1918 (Box 2)
  - August 1918 (Box 2)
  - September-October 1918 (Box 2)
  - November 1918 (Box 2)
  - December 1918 (Box 2)
  - 1919 undated (Box 2)
  - January 1-15, 1919 (Box 2)
  - January 16-31, 1919 (Box 2)
  - February 1-14, 1919 (Box 2)
  - February 15-28, 1919 (Box 2)
  - March 1-10, 1919 (Box 2)
  - March 11-20, 1919 (Box 2)
  - March 21-31, 1919 (Box 2)
  - April 1-15, 1919 (Box 2)
  - April 16-30, 1919 (Box 2)
  - May-June 1919 (Box 2)
  - July 1919 (Box 3)
  - August 1919 (Box 3)
  - September-October 1919 (Box 3)
  - November-December 1919 (Box 3)
  - January 1920 (Box 3)
  - February-March 1920 (Box 3)
  - April-June 1920 (Box 3)
  - July-November 1920 (Box 3)
  - December 1-10, 1920 (Box 3)
  - December 11-31, 1920 (Box 3)
  - circa 1921 (Box 3)
  - January 1-15, 1921 (Box 3)
  - January 16-31, 1921 (Box 3)
  - February 1-10, 1921 (Box 3)
  - February 11-20, 1921 (Box 3)
  - February 21-28, 1921 (Box 3)
  - March 1-10, 1921 (Box 3)
  - March 11-20, 1921 (Box 3)
  - March 21-31, 1921 (Box 3)
  - April 1-15, 1921 (Box 3)
  - April 16-30, 1921 (Box 3)
  - May-December 1921 (Box 3)
  - 1922 (Box 3)
  - January-September 1923 (Box 3)
  - October 1923 (Box 3)
  - November 1-15, 1923 (Box 3)
  - November 16-30, 1923 (Box 3)
  - December 1-10, 1923 (Box 3)
  - December 11-20, 1923 (Box 3)
  - December 21-31, 1923 (Box 3)
  - January 1-20, 1924 (Box 3)
  - January 21-25, 1924 (Box 3)
  - January 26-31, 1924 (Box 3)
  - February-April 1924 (Box 3)
  - May 1-28, 1924 (Box 4)
  - May 29-31, 1924 (Box 4)
  - June 1-10, 1924 (Box 4)
  - June 11-20, 1924 (Box 4)
  - June 21-30, 1924 (Box 4)
  - July 1-5, 1924 (Box 4)
  - July 6-10, 1924 (Box 4)
  - July 11-15, 1924 (Box 4)
  - July 16-20, 1924 (Box 4)
  - July 21-25, 1924 (Box 4)
  - July 26-31, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 1-5, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 6-10, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 11-15, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 16-18, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 19-20, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 21-25, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 26-27, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 28-29, 1924 (Box 4)
  - August 30-31, 1924 (Box 4)
  - September 1-2, 1924 (Box 4)
  - September 3-5, 1924 (Box 4)
  - September 6-10, 1924 (Box 4)
  - September 11-20, 1924 (Box 4)
  - September 21-30, 1924 (Box 4)
  - October 1924 (Box 4)
  - November 1924 (Box 4)
  - December 1-15, 1924 (Box 4)
  - December 16-31, 1924 (Box 4)
  - January 1-15, 1925 (Box 4)
  - January 16-31, 1925 (Box 4)
  - February 1-15, 1925 (Box 4)
  - February 16-28, 1925 (Box 4)
  - March 1-15, 1925 (Box 4)
  - March 16-31, 1925 (Box 4)
  - April 1925 (Box 4)
  - May-June 1925 (Box 4)
  - July 1925 (Box 4)
  - August-September 1925 (Box 4)
  - October-November 1925 (Box 4)
  - December 1925 (Box 4)
  - circa 1926 (Box 5)
  - January 1926 (Box 5)
  - February 1926 (Box 5)
  - March 1926 (Box 5)
  - April 1926 (Box 5)
  - May 1926 (Box 5)
  - June 1926 (Box 5)
  - July 1926 (Box 5)
  - August 1926 (Box 5)
  - September-November 1926 (Box 5)
  - 1928-1929 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Papers and Scrapbooks
  - Papers, concerning the joint legislative committee to investigate the Michigan Community Council Commission, 1920-1921, 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 5)
  - Papers, concerning the Conference of Progressive State Granges, 1910-1912 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Letters of Condolence 1930, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks, 2 volumes
    - 1881-1930 (Box 5)
      (mostly obituaries)
    - 1922-1924 (Volume 1)
      (politics)
  - Diary, 1923-1926 (Box 5)
  - Postcards, Greeting cards, etc. (Box 5)
- Photographs
  The photographs series includes a tintype of Baker and wife, 1891; a tintype of Baker with others at National Grange Convention, 1911; photographs of barn raising, 1905, probably in Cheboygan County, Michigan; and photographs of Baker in the State Legislature and Legislative Committee Room.
  - Photographs and tintypes, 1 envelopes (Box 5)
Partial Index to Correspondence
Among the more significant individuals and organizations represented in the correspondence series are:
All American Co-operative Commission
1920; 1921; Feb. 16, 1925; Jan. 4, 1926
Ancient Order of Gleaners
1908; 1912; 1916; 1917; 1918; 1919; 1920; 1921; Jan. 19, 1922; 1923; 1924; 1925; 1926
Anti-Saloon League of Michigan
Aug. 13, 1918; Sept. 7, 1918
Bourne, Jonathan, 1855-1940
Dec. 31, 1910; Jan. 16, 1911; Mar. 14, 1911
Briggs, Walter Owen, 1877-1952
Feb. 7, 1919
Campbell, Colin Percy, 1877-
July 27, 1907; Aug. 7, 1908; Aug. 11, 1908; Nov. 7, 1908
Clardy, Kit Francis, 1892-
May 11, 1926; May 25, 1926; June 11, 1926; Aug. 13, 1926
Conference for Progressive Political Action
Mar. 1, 1924; June 6, 1924; June 19, 1924; July 28, 1924
Conference of Progressive State Granges
1911; 1912
Couzens, James Joseph, 1872-1936
Jan. 18, 1924; Aug. 18, 1925; Aug. 24, 1925; Jan. 7, 1926
Cramton, Louis Convers, 1875-1966
Aug. 2, 1912; Aug. 8, 1912; Jan. 13, 1915; Feb. 27, 1920; Feb. 12, 1921; Mar. 5, 1921; Nov. 21, 1923
Currie, Gilbert Archibald, 1882-1960
July 25, 1911; Sept. 12, 1911; Oct. 30, 1911; May 21, 1912
DeFoe, Murl Holcomb, 1879-
Sept. 13, 1923; Oct. 16, 1923
Detroit Municipal League
Mar. 3, 1911
Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943
Oct. 7, 1908; 1926, undated; Jan. 19, 1926; June 24, 1926; Aug. 31, 1926
Earle, Horatio Sawyer, 1855-1935
Jan. 3, 1908; Feb. 3, 1908; June 5, 1912
Ellis, George Edwin, 1864-
Dec. 21, 1911
Employers' Association of Detroit
1911
Farmer's Federal Tax League of America
Apr. 11, 1921
Farmers' National Committee on Postal Reform
1912
Farmers' National Committee on Transportation
Feb. 26, 1919
Farmers' National Committee on War Finance
1917; 1918
Farmers' National Council
1919; 1920; 1921; Jan. 16, 1922; 1923; 1924; 1925
Fellows, Grant, 1865-1929
1916
Ferris, Woodbridge Nathan, 1853-1928
Apr. 15, 1926
Fletcher, Frank Ward, 1853-1922
Dec. 7, 1918; Dec. 10, 1918; Feb. 28, 1919
Fuller, Oramel B., 1858-
July 27, 1916; Sept. 14, 1916; Sept. 2, 1916; May 28, 1917; Jan. 18, 1918; Nov. 8, 1918; Mar. 26, 1919; Apr. 20, 1921; Jan. 13, 1925
Gardner, Obadiah, 1850-1938
1912
Grayling. Salling, Hanson and Company.
Mar. 18, 1921
Green, Fred Warren, 1872-1936
Dec. 1918; Feb. 25, 1918; Mar. 25, 1921; 1923; May 23, 1924; June 4, 1924; Oct. 17, 1924; Dec. 1924; Mar. 1925; May 16, 1925; July 29, 1925; Aug. 25, 1925; Oct. 2, 1925; Nov. 7, 1925; Dec. 1925; Jan. 1926; Apr. 26, 1926; Sept. 20, 1926
Grenell, Judson, 1847-
Jan. 20, 1911
Groesbeck, Alexander J., 1873-1953
Nov. 29, 1920; Dec. 10, 1920
Hampton, George P., d. 1921
1911; 1912; 1915; 1916; 1917; 1918; 1919; 1920; 1921
Helme, James W., 1860-1938
May 24, 1910; July 6, 1911; July 8, 1911; Aug. 14, 1911; May 31, 1912; 1916; Apr. 10, 1919; Aug. 14, 1919
Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1957
Mar. 1921; Apr. 1921; May 11, 1921; July 1924; Aug. 1924
Howe, Frederic Clemson, 1867-1940
Mar. 20, 1911
James, William Francis, 1873-1945
Feb. 1912; July 1, 1912; Sept. 21, 1912; Jan. 1917; Feb. 5, 1917; May 1, 1917; June 2, 1917; 1918; Feb. 9, 1921
Jeffries, Edward J., 1900-1950
Oct. 23, 1919; Nov. 16, 1923; Dec. 24, 1923; Jan. 25, 1924
Ketchum, John Clark, 1873-1941
Dec. 22, 1911
King, Paul Howard, 1879-1942
Feb. 14, 1912
Knox, Frank, 1874-1944
Jan. 1911; Feb. 4, 1911; Mar. 1911; July 1911; Sept. 1911; Oct. 1911; Nov. 1911; Dec. 1911; Jan. 1912; July 1912; Jan. 2, 1917
LaFollette, Robert Marion, 1855-1925
Feb. 11, 1921; Apr. 8, 1921; Apr. 22, 1921; Jan. 11, 1924; Feb. 3, 1925
Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961
June 26, 1924; 1926
League of American Sportsmen
Feb. 8, 1911
Lemke, William, 1878-1950
Mar. 28, 1921
Loud, George Alvin, 1852-1925
1906; 1908; 1911; 1912
Lowden, Frank Orren, 1861-1943
Mar. 8, 1920
Lutheran Church. Missouri Synod. Michigan District. Lutheran Schools Committee
Letter, Aug. 15, 1924 concerning the parochial school amendment
McGregor, Tracy W., 1869-1936
Jan. 11, 1911
Maples, Carl Edgar, 1874-1939
Feb. 22, 1919
Marsh, Benjamin Clarke, 1877-
1919; 1920; 1921; Jan. 16, 1922; 1923; 1924; 1925; 1926
Martel, Frank Xavier, 1888-
Feb. 6, 1925
Martindale, Frederick C., 1865-
Aug. 31, 1911; 1919; 1920; 1921; 1926
Michigan Federation of Labor
Feb. 5, 1921; Apr. 4, 1921; Aug. 27, 1923; Oct. 5, 1923; July 28, 1924
Michigan Home Rule League
Sept. 19, 1916
Michigan Potato Growers Exchange
1919; 1920; 1921; 1923; 1924; 1925
Michigan State Federation of Women's Clubs
Mar. 12, 1911
Modern Woodmen of America
Jan. 17, 1907; 1908; 1909; 1911; 1912; 1914; 1915; 1916; 1917; 1918; 1919; 1920; 1921; 1925
Musselman, Amos S., 1851-
July 27, 1909
National Milk Producers Federation
1920
National Non-partisan League
1919; Feb. 16, 1921; Feb. 26, 1921; Mar. 12, 1921
National Progressive Republican League
Mar. 20, 1911
Osborn, Chase Salmon, 1860-1949
July 1911; Oct. 10, 1911; Dec. 1911; Jan. 22, 1912; Feb. 9, 1912; June 15, 1912; July 1912; Sept. 26, 1912; Jan. 1917; Dec. 29, 1917; 1918?; Jan. 1918; Dec. 20, 1918; Feb. 26, 1919; Dec. 1919; May 20, 1920; Mar. 1, 1921; Sept. 10, 1924; Dec. 21, 1924; Jan. 2, 1925; Feb. 2, 1925; Dec. 30, 1925; Sept. 4, 1926
People's Legislative Service
Apr. 8, 1921; Feb. 3, 1925
People's Reconstruction League
1921; 1923; 1925; 1926
Pettigrew, Richard Franklin, 1848-1926
Oct. 19, 1923
Powers, Perry Francis, 1857-1945
July 13, 1911
Progressive Republicans' League of Michigan
Jan. 16, 1911; Jan. 27, 1911; Feb. 7, 1911
Progressive Voters League of Michigan
Nov. 14, 1923
Rural Credit League of America
1915; 1916
Scott, Frank Douglas, 1878-1951
Apr. 26, 1921; May 24, 1924; Apr. 29, 1926
Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934
Oct. 1917; Mar. 19, 1920
Smith, John W., 1883-
Nov. 22, 1924; Jan. 22, 1925; Dec. 3, 1925
Smith, William Alden, 1859-1932
Feb. 6, 1911; Feb. 9, 1911; Mar. 5, 1911
Townsend, Charles Elroy, 1856-1924
Jan. 23, 1911; July 17, 1911; Mar. 31, 1916; Apr. 20, 1916; Aug. 7, 1916; Sept. 28, 1918; Sept. 22, 1919
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951
Feb. 27, 1919; Mar. 15, 1919; July 17, 1924
Wallace, Henry Cantwell, 1866-1924
Sept. 27, 1923
Warner, Fred Maltby, 1865-1923
Mar. 6, 1908
Watkins, Lucius Whitney, 1873-
June 14, 1912; Aug. 13, 1912
Wesselius, Sybrant, 1859-
Apr. 13, 1912; Nov. 27, 1923; May 1924; July 1924; Sept. 5, 1924
Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953
Apr. 27, 1921